<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>lithology on Andy McDonald</title>
    <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/tags/lithology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in lithology on Andy McDonald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://andymcdgeo.github.io/tags/lithology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Lithology Data on a Well Log Plot Using Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-02-07-displaying-lithology-on-log-plots-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-02-07-displaying-lithology-on-log-plots-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Adding lithology information to a well log plot can enhance a petrophysical or geological interpretation. It can be used to understand why some log responses may behave the way they do. This data may have been sourced from a previous mineralogical interpretation or from mud logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Lithology Data on a Well Log Plot Using Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-01-31-displaying-logging-while-drill-lwd-image-logs-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-01-31-displaying-logging-while-drill-lwd-image-logs-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Borehole image logs are false-color pseudo images of the borehole wall generated from different logging measurements/tools. How borehole images are acquired differs between wireline logging and logging while drilling (LWD). In the wireline environment measurements are made from buttons on pads that are pressed up against the borehole wall and provide limited coverage, but at a high resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Lithology Data on a Well Log Plot Using Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-01-27-enhancing-visualisation-of-well-logs-with-plot-fills/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-01-27-enhancing-visualisation-of-well-logs-with-plot-fills/</guid>
      <description>Matplotlib is a great library to work with in Python and it is one that I always go back to time and time again to work with well logs. Due to its high degree of flexibility it can be tricky to get started with it at first, but once you have mastered the basics it can become a powerful tool for data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
