<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Python on Andy McDonald</title>
    <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/categories/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Python on Andy McDonald</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://andymcdgeo.github.io/categories/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Loading Well Log Data From DLIS using Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-04-21-loading-well-log-data-from-dlis-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-04-21-loading-well-log-data-from-dlis-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Loading Well Log Data From DLIS using Python A short tutorial on loading and displaying processed acoustic waveform data using dlisio and matplotlib Introduction There are a number of different formats that well log and petrophysical data can be stored in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Formation Data to a Well Log Plot</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-02-28-adding-formation-data-to-a-well-log-plot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-02-28-adding-formation-data-to-a-well-log-plot/</guid>
      <description>Taking well log plots one step further using Python and matplotlib Well log plots are a common visualization tool within geoscience and petrophysics. They allow easy visualization of data (for example, Gamma Ray, Neutron Porosity, Bulk Density, etc) that has been acquired along the length (depth) of a wellbore.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading Multiple Well Log LAS Files Using Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-02-14-loading-multiple-well-log-las-files-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-02-14-loading-multiple-well-log-las-files-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Appending Multiple LAS Files to a Pandas Dataframe Log ASCII Standard (LAS) files are a common Oil &amp;amp; Gas industry format for storing and transferring well log data. The data contained within is used to analyze and understand the subsurface, as well as identify potential hydrocarbon reserves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Lithology Data on a Well Log Plot Using Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-02-07-displaying-lithology-on-log-plots-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-02-07-displaying-lithology-on-log-plots-using-python/</guid>
      <description>Adding lithology information to a well log plot can enhance a petrophysical or geological interpretation. It can be used to understand why some log responses may behave the way they do. This data may have been sourced from a previous mineralogical interpretation or from mud logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Lithology Data on a Well Log Plot Using Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-01-31-displaying-logging-while-drill-lwd-image-logs-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-01-31-displaying-logging-while-drill-lwd-image-logs-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Borehole image logs are false-color pseudo images of the borehole wall generated from different logging measurements/tools. How borehole images are acquired differs between wireline logging and logging while drilling (LWD). In the wireline environment measurements are made from buttons on pads that are pressed up against the borehole wall and provide limited coverage, but at a high resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Displaying Lithology Data on a Well Log Plot Using Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-01-27-enhancing-visualisation-of-well-logs-with-plot-fills/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2021-01-27-enhancing-visualisation-of-well-logs-with-plot-fills/</guid>
      <description>Matplotlib is a great library to work with in Python and it is one that I always go back to time and time again to work with well logs. Due to its high degree of flexibility it can be tricky to get started with it at first, but once you have mastered the basics it can become a powerful tool for data visualization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porosity-Permeability Relationships Using Linear Regression in Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-12-28-porosity-permeability-relationships-using-linear-regression-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-12-28-porosity-permeability-relationships-using-linear-regression-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Core data analysis is a key component in the evaluation of a field or discovery, as it provides direct samples of the geological formations in the subsurface over the interval of interest. It is often considered the ‘ground truth’ by many and is used as a reference for calibrating well log measurements and petrophysical analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Porosity-Permeability Relationships Using Linear Regression in Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-11-01-exploratory-data-analysis-with-well-log-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-11-01-exploratory-data-analysis-with-well-log-data/</guid>
      <description>Once data has been collated and sorted through, the next step in the Data Science process is to carry out Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA). This step allows us to identify patterns within the data, understand relationships between the features (well logs) and identify possible outliers that may exist within the dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visualising Well Data Coverage Using matplotlib</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-10-26-visualising-well-data-coverage-using-matplotlib/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-10-26-visualising-well-data-coverage-using-matplotlib/</guid>
      <description>Exploratory Data Analysis (EDA) is an integral part of Data Science. The same is true for the petrophysical domain and can often be referred to as the Log QC or data review stage of a project. It is at this stage that we begin to go through the data in detail and identify what data we really have, where we have it and what is the quality of the gathered data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Petrophysics: Gamma Ray Normalization in Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-10-18-petrophysics-gamma-ray-normalisation-in-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-10-18-petrophysics-gamma-ray-normalisation-in-python/</guid>
      <description>Normalization of well log data is a common and routine process within a petrophysical workflow and is used to correct for variations in logging curves between wells. These variations can arise due a number of different reasons such as incorrect tool calibrations, varying tool vintage and changes in borehole environmental conditions between the wells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Loading and Displaying Well Log Data from LAS Files with Python</title>
      <link>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-08-30-loading-and-displaying-well-log-data-from-las-files-with-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://andymcdgeo.github.io/blog/2020-08-30-loading-and-displaying-well-log-data-from-las-files-with-python/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who has worked or is currently working within the oil and gas industry will understand that there are a large variety of formats that well log data can be stored in. Some of the common formats that we as petrophysicists work with include LAS, ASCII and CSV files.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
